# Prashant Sharma

Sr. Software Engineer

LinkedIn | GitHub | Udemy Certs

#### HackerRank Certificates & Badges

- Java Gold Level 5★
- Problem Solving Gold Level - 5★
- SQL Silver Level 4★

### Contact

#### E-mail

ps.arraha@gmail.com

#### Mobile

+49 151 6724 9256

#### **Address**

Berlin, 10439

### Skills

Java/J2EE

Spring & Spring Boot

Microservice & RESTful Web Service

CI/CD: GitHub, Docker, k8s, Jenkins & Cloud Foundry

TDD: Junit & Cucumber framework

ORM: JPA & Hibernate

A skilled, hardworking and well-organized Senior Software Engineer with 8.5 years of experience in the design and development of high-performing software. Effective in delivering useful, efficient and cost-effective products. Proficiency with all phases of the product lifecycle (SDLC), including requirements gathering, design, implementation, testing, integration, and support.

## **Work History**

2022-04- Senior Software Engineer – Zalando SE | Berlin, Germany

Current Zalando Lounge: Customer Facing Applications

Microservice based Java & Spring boot Applications

**Project Description:** Responsible for new user registration & existing user login to the Zalando Lounge application via website & app (Android & iOS). Updating customer data & preferences for daily or weekly newsletters.

**Role:** Working as Senior Java Developer in Agile team of 7 members.

#### Technologies in use:

- Backend: Microservice architecture, Java, Spring Boot & Reactive.
- DB PostgreSQL, AWS Dynamo DB.
- Event Streaming: Nakadi (Kafka)
- JMS: ActiveMO
- Web Service: RESTful & SOAP.
- Orchestration: Kubernetes (k8s)
- Deployment: On Cloud AWS
- CI/CD tool: Docker & Continuous Delivery Platform.
- App monitoring & Logs: Grafana, Lightstep & Scylar
- SCM: GitHub
- IDE & build tool: IntelliJ, maven, gradel

2021-06- Senior Consultant – Thoughtworks | Pune, MH

2022 - 03 Periscope - McKinsey & Company

Microservice based Scala, Spark & Golang App | July'21 - March'22

**Project Description:** Pricing recommendation & Management Product for a Consulting major using advanced methodologies and proprietary recommendation algorithms, this product provides an integrated price setting and management solutions for its customers.

Role: Working as Senior Developer in a scrum team of 8 members.

#### Technologies & Tools in use:

Microservice architecture, Scala, Spark, Golang with DB –
PostgreSQL, Elastic Search, AWS & Azure, Jenkins, GoCD,
Docker, RESTful & gRPC & GitLab, ActiveMQ & Amazon SQS,
New Relic, Splunk, IntelliJ, sbt, goMod

Security: Sonar & Veracode

Performance & Load Testing: Gatling scripts

ServiceNow: Technical & Customer support

Algorithms & Design Pattern implementation

2018-03 – Sr. Software Engineer - John Deere - Pune, Maharashtra

## John Deere Custom Performance | Spring Boot | Microservice based Java App | Mar'18 – June'21

#### Role:

2021-06

Worked as a T-Developer in a product team of 8 members following Agile methodology & DevSecOps. Also, a Tier-3 support person who works on the incidents reported in ServiceNow by the users. Had a working Scrum master experience of 1.2 years after getting certified for CSM from Scrum Alliance.

#### **Primary Responsibilities:**

- Designing & developing Java applications with the given product specifications in form of HLD & LLD using Spring frameworks like Spring Boot, Spring data JPA, Spring boot Actuator & Spring Cloud.
- Writing efficient & testable production code by following standard principles like SOLID, design patterns, clean code & Junit test cases with coverage of minimum 85%.
- Writing functional tests & load/performance testing scripts in Java & Scala for developed RESTful APIs using Cucumber & Gatling framework respectively.
- Writing deployment scripts in Jenkinsfile & DSLs to deploy java apps on Cloud Foundry using Jenkins.

#### Also, responsible for:

- Collaborating with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on users' requirements
- Sharing ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivering updates on deadlines, designs & enhancements.
- Discuss issues with customers, collect feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns using IT technologies.
- Mentoring junior developers and engineers, teaching skills in Java, Jenkins, Load testing, Kibana & AppDynamics, ServiceNow to improve overall team performance.

#### Technologies used:

- Deployment: On Cloud Cloud Foundry
- CI/CD tool: Jenkins
- Backend: Java, Spring Framework, Spring boot, Hibernate,
   JPA with Microservice architecture. SQL DB DB2 & Oracle
- Open Stack To host UI, Jenkins & logging tool KIBANA
- Web Service: RESTful
- SCM: GitHub
- Code Quality: Sonar Qube
- Security & Vulnerability scan: Veracode
- JMS: ActiveMQ
- IDE & build tool: IntelliJ & Maven
- App monitoring: AppDynamics
- API Documentation: Open API 3.0 / Swagger 3

2017-12 - Technology Analyst - Infosys, Pune, Maharashtra
2018-03 Was not mapped to any project.

## 2014-10 – Software Engineer – Tech Mahindra, Pune, Maharashtra 2017-12 Worked as a Java developer in 2 AT&T projects.

#### a. Design Studio | Spring Boot Web App | Microservice | Aug'16 - Dec'17

Developed & exposed RESTful APIs based on the specifications provided by the client in the form of High-Level Document (HLD) using technologies Core Java, Spring & Spring boot, MVC architecture, Restful Web Services, JSON, Design patterns, XML tested the developed functionalities using Swagger 2.0. Written JUnit test cases with code coverage of >70%.

Attended daily calls scheduled with clients to update. development status.

#### Tools used:

 IDE: Spring Tool Suite (STS), Build Tool: Maven, SCM: Bit Bucket & GitHub, CI/ CD tool: Jenkins, Code Quality checks using SONAR.

## b. Virtual Ticketing Management | Monolith Web App |Feb'15 - Aug'16

 Developed requirements based on the specifications provided by the client in the form of High-Level Document (HLD) & Visual design (VD) using Java/J2EE, Web Services, XML, SQL, Spring Framework & MVC.

#### Tools used:

 Eclipse, Maven, SVN, Server: Dragonfly, Rapid UI Designer (Raap designer)

## Certification

2018-12 Certified Scrum Master (**CSM**), Scrum Alliance, 2018-20

## **Education**

2010-08 – B-Tech: Electronics and Communications Engineering

2014-06 Bengal Institute of Technology & Management

Shanti Niketan, West Bengal

DGPA: 8.18